<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Isaac Reforged</name>
    <directory>isaac reforged</directory>
    <id>2349100735</id>
    <description>This mod aims to add and rebalance characters, synergies, and transformations, while remaining faithful to the vanilla experience.

Supports External Item Descriptions!
Supports Mod Config Menu!
Supports Revelations!
Supports Fiend Folio!
&amp; More!

All changes are configurable with the Mod Config Menu. (May require a restart during a run)

Spritework commissioned by the very talented and wonderful Blind, the Bound Demon. 

[h1]Misc Features:[/h1]
[list]
  [*]Eternal Chests will always pay out with something, and have a small chance to teleport you to an Angel Room. Consumes golden keys!
  [*]Several Transformations have been buffed or modified.
  [*]All characters start with innate and starting trinkets.
  [*]The Lost never loses Holy Mantle on rerolls. The D4 however, takes longer to charge.
  [*]When Cain collects Cain's other eye, he gets 20/20 vision.
  [*]Troll Bombs will uniformly detonate after 2 seconds.
  [*]Tinted Ground, a once per floor opportunity to a crawlspace and a chance to enter the black market!
[/list]

[h1]Pills[/h1]
[list]
  [*]I Found Pills gives a random pill effect.
  [*]R U a Wizard? grants a minor tears up for its duration.
  [*]Bad Gas deals scales with your damage.
  [*]Addicted spawns 1 - 3 additional pills in the room.
  [*]+0.1 Damage Up / -0.1 Damage Down pills
  [*]+0.1 Shotspeed Up / -0.1 Shotspeed Down pills.
[/list]

[h1]New Items:[/h1]
[list]
  [*]6 Active Items
  [*]8 Passive Items
  [*]2 Trinkets
[/list]

[h1]Transformations:[/h1]
The Bob Transformation
[list]
  [*]Grants all passive items in the transformation
  [*]Bob's Bladder contributes to the transformation
[/list]
The Conjoined Transformation
[list]
  [*]Grants an extra trinket slot
  [*]Gives the cancer trinket
[/list]
The Oh Crap Transformation 
[list]
  [*]Grants all passive items in the transformation
  [*]Butt Bombs, No. 2, Farting Baby, and Number One all additionally contribute to the transformation
[/list]
The Adult Transformation
[list]
  [*]Gives Depression
[/list]
The Spider Baby Transformation
[list]
  [*]Grants Spider Bite, Spider Mod, and Spider Baby
[/list]
The Seraphim Transformation
[list]
  [*]Gives the Soul
[/list]
The Fun Guy Transformation
[list]
  [*]Grants all passive items in the transformation except for God's Flesh
[/list]
The Beelzbub Transformation
[list]
  [*]Gives Muligan and 3 Pretty Flies
[/list]
The Duality Transformation
[list]
  [*]Gives Duality and Eucharist
  [*]Achieved by holding the Left and Right Hands, or having Dark Prince's Crown and Crown of Light.
[/list]
The Magneto Transformation
[list]
  [*]requires three of the following: Magneto, Strange Attractor, Metal Plate, Broken Magnet, and Super Magnet.
  [*]Gives all passive items in the transformation and reflects 100% of enemy shots back at them.
[/list]
Yes Mother?
[list]
  [*]Every 30 seconds, a friendly Mom's Foot will attack enemies.
[/list]
The Greed Transformation
[list]
  [*]requires three out of (Money = Power, A Quarter, A Dollar, Greed's Gullet, Eye of Greed, Head of the Keeper).
  [*]Grants the effects of rib of greed, silver dollar, a greed costume, and when you are damaged, you have a chance to spawn coins.
[/list]
The Cyborg Transformation
[list]
  [*]requires six out of (The Battery, 9 Volt, Car Battery, Tech.5, Technology, Technology 2, Metal Plate, Robo-Baby, Robo-Baby 2.0, Technology Zero, Tech X, Spider Mod).
  [*]Grants Metal Plate if not collected, a metallic costume, and the ability to use heart pickups to partially charge active items.
[/list]
The Butcher Transformation
[list]
  [*]requires five out of (Cricket's Head, Goat Head, Tammy's Head, Guppy's Head, Head of Krampus, Head of the Keeper, Bob's Rotten Head).
  [*]Grants Bloody Lust and Lusty Blood if not collected, and a serial killer costume.
[/list]
The Astrologer Transformation
[list]
  [*]requires five out of (Aquarius, Aries, Cancer, Capricorn, Gemini, Leo, Libra, Pisces, Sagittarius, Scorpio, Taurus, Virgo, Zodiac).
  [*]Grants a higher chance to encounter the rest of the zodiac signs, and a neat wizard cloak.
[/list]
The Master Alchemist Transformation
[list]
  [*]requires three of (The Mind, The Body, The Soul, Chaos, Philospher's Stone).
  [*]Grants any missing passive items from the set, and a godhead costume.
[/list]
The Bag of Holding Transformation
[list]
  [*]requires four of (Bomb Bag, Rune Bag, Sack of Pennies, Sack of Sacks, Mystery Sack, Key Sack, Lil Chest).
  [*]Combines existing familiars into one familiar, that drops a plethora of consumables.
[/list]
The Dungeon Delver Transformation
[list]
  [*]requires five of (We Need to go Deeper, Spelunker Hat, Notched Axe, Mine Crafter, Treasure Map, Blue Map, The Compass, A Lump of Coal, Mama Mega!).
  [*]Grants Spelunker Hat if not collected, Curse of Darkness, an explorer's costume, and a x1.1 damage multiplier for every floor completed.
[/list]
The Card Dealer Transformation
[list]
  [*]requires four of (Portable Slot, Deck of Cards, Crooked Penny, Magic 8 Ball, Tarot Cloth, Crystal Ball, Magic Fingers, Loaded Deck).
  [*]Grants a chance for killed enemies to drop tarot cards, and a tuxedo costume.
[/list]
The Trick or Treat Transformation
[list]
  [*]requires four of (Death's Touch, Host Hat, Ouija Board, Lil Haunt, Dry Baby, Bozo, Pop!, Apple!, Finger!).
  [*]Grants a halloween costume, and fears any enemies that get too close.
[/list]
The Bony Transformation
[list]
  [*]requires four of (Jaw Bone, Slipped Rib, Pointy Rib, Brittle Bones, Compound Fracture, Book of the Dead, Marrow, Skeleton Key).
  [*]Grants Compound Fracture if not collected, a bony costume, and a chance to gain an empty bone heart when taking damage.
[/list]
The Stony Transformation
[list]
  [*]requires four of (Gnawed Leaf, Lump of Coal, Flat Stone, The Small Rock, Lucky Rock, Shiny Rock, Callus).
  [*]Grants immunity to spikes and brimstone lasers. Grants a stony costume.
[/list]
The Eternal Transformation
[list]
  [*]requires 12 eternal hearts.
  [*]Grants Dead Dove if not collected, a pretty fly, and an eternal costume.
[/list]
The Cricket Transformation
[list]
  [*]requires three of (Cricket's Head, Cricket's Body, Cricket's Paw, Cricket's Collar, Dog Tooth, (Dinner, Dessert, A Snack).
  [*]Grants any missing passive items from the set, and a cricket costume.
[/list]
The Tammy Transformation
[list]
  [*]requires three of (Tammy's Head, Tammy's Eyes, Tammy's Body, Tammy's Tail,  Tammy's Paw).
  [*]Grants any missing passive items from the set, and a tammy costume.
[/list]

[h1]Starting Trinkets:[/h1]
[list]
  [*]Isaac gets the effect of Golden Horse Shoe and starts with Bag Lunch
  [*]Magdalene gets the effect of Purple Heart and starts with Maggy's Faith
  [*]Cain gets the effect of Lucky Toe and starts with Paper Clip 
  [*]Judas gets the effect of Black Feather and starts with Judas' Tongue 
  [*]XXX gets the effect of Meconium and starts with Petrified Poop
  [*]Eve gets the effect of Eve's Bird Foot and starts with Wish Bone 
  [*]Samson gets the effect of Samson's Lock and starts with Child's Heart
  [*]Azazel gets the effect of Tape Worm and starts with Daemon's Tail
  [*]Lazarus gets the effect of Lost Cork and starts with Bible Tract
  [*]Eden gets the effect of Error (404)
  [*]The Lost gets the Faded Polaroid and starts with Fragmented Card
  [*]Lilith gets the effect of Child Leash and starts with Blind Rage
  [*]The Keeper gets the effect of Rib of Greed and starts with Store Key
  [*]Apollyon gets the effect of Callus and starts with Locust of Conquest 
  [*]The Forgotten gets the effect of Crow Heart and starts with Finger Bone
[/list]

Let me know if you enjoy the mod, find any bugs, have any suggestions or criticisms!</description>
    <version>1.8</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Items"/>
    <tag id="Active Items"/>
    <tag id="Trinkets"/>
    <tag id="Pills"/>
    <tag id="Cards"/>
    <tag id="Pickups"/>
    <tag id="Player Characters"/>
    <tag id="Familiars"/>
    <tag id="Hazards"/>
    <tag id="Tweaks"/>
    <tag id="Removals"/>
    <tag id="Graphics"/>
    <tag id="Sound Effects"/>
</metadata>
